WHISPER IT LIKE A CURSE!
Helter Skelter is a crime, drama, thriller film directed by Tom Gries.
The investigation of two horrific mass murders leads to the capture and trial
of the psychotic pseudo-hippie Charles Manson and his "family".
Vincent Bugliosi, played by George DiCenzo.
Charles Manson, played by Steve Railsback.
Susan Atkins, played by Nancy Wolfe.
Linda Kasabian, played by Marilyn Burns.
Patricia Krenwinkel, played by Christina Hart.
Leslie Van Houten, played by Cathey Paine.
Helter Skelter is a 1976 American true crime drama thriller television film based
on the 1974 book by prosecutor Vincent Bugliosi and Curt Gentry.
In the United States, it aired over two nights.
In some countries it was shown in cinemas, with additional footage
including nudity, profanity, and more violence.
The movie is based on the murders committed by the Charles Manson Family.
The best-known victim was pregnant actress Sharon Tate.
The title was taken from the 1968 Beatles' song of the same name.
According to the theory put forward by the prosecution, Manson used the term for an anticipated race war, and "healter
skelter" [sic] was scrawled in blood on the refrigerator door at the home of victims Rosemary and Leno LaBianca.
It recounts the murders Manson committed, the investigation, and the 1970-71 trial, in which prosecutor Vincent
Bugliosi attempted to draw connections between the Manson family and his violent convictions.
The 1976 film, directed by Tom Gries, stars Steve Railsback
as Manson and George DiCenzo as Bugliosi.
Writer JP Miller received a 1977 Edgar Award from the Mystery Writers
of America for Best TV Feature or Mini-series Teleplay.
In 2004, the book was adapted for a second made-for-TV movie, written and
directed by John Gray and featuring Jeremy Davies as Manson.
The film explores themes of commune, historical
figure, trial, serial killer, hollywood.
The tone is dark and emotional and intense.